[ 

Who is calling?](https://www.tellows.co.uk/ "tellows - the community for calls, phone spam and complaints")

* Contact
* Country
    * Country: EgyptAlgeriaUnited Arab EmiratesArgentinaAustraliaBelgiumBrazilChileChinaDenmarkGermanyFinnland FranceGreeceUnited KingdomHong KongIndiaIndonesiaIranIrelandIsraelItalyJapanColombiaMexicoNew ZealandNetherlandsNigeriaNorwayAustriaPakistanPeruPhilippinesPolandPortugalRussiaSaudi ArabiaSwedenSwitzerlandSingaporeSloveniaSpainSouth AfricaSouth KoreaTaiwanCzech RepublicTurkeyUkraineHungaryUSA, CanadaVenezuelaBelarus

Privacy Policy
==============

_Last updated: 22.09.2023_

* General
At tellows, we are keenly aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to protect your privacy. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining of our online information practices, including how we collect and use the information you may provide to us on the website, and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. With regard to your personal data, we observe the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG), the German Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the Teleservices Data Protection Act (TDDSG) and the data protection regulations of the European Union.  
  
This disclaimer refers only to our sites. Third parties might offer hyperlinks to other websites which may have information policies and practices different from ours. We do not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies, practices, or the content of any third party websites. Once you’ve left our websites via such a link or by clicking on an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party or advertiser site to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you.  
  
Personal data are single details about personal or factual circumstances of a certain or a definable natural person. Information that can identify a person or make him identifiable.  
  
Hereafter, we will explain what information is collected and for what purpose.* Data Collection and Processing
We hereby confirm that the collection, processing and use of personal data is done in compliance with all data protection regulations and is in adherence with the laws mentioned above, specifically the GDPR Art. 6 s. 1 a and the CCPA alongside the other data protection laws of California. This means we only process data in case of legitimate interest according to Art. 6 s. 1 f GDPR (e.g. for analysis, optimization and protection of the tellows online offerings) or under permission of processing by the user (e.g. accepting requests).  
  
We have technical (e.g. SSL encryption), contractual (e.g. data processing agreement) and organizational measures (e.g. access restrictions) in place to ensure that the rules of the GDPR are abided by and that data is secure from access and manipulation.  
  
It is possible to access our website without offering any personal information. We have also taken measures to anonymize (see paragraph Google Analytics), i.e. an analysis data acquisition only serves to improve our offerings and does not allow for any inferences about individuals.  
  
We process the following categories of data which are relevant for using the tellows website and services or are necessary for contacting:

* master data (e.g. name)
* contact data (e.g. phone number, email)
* content entry data (e.g. text/ comment entry, access times)
* meta data (e.g. IP address)

* Deletion of tellows account and associated comments
If you have created a tellows account, you can delete it at any time. To do so, log in to your [member area.](https://www.tellows.co.uk/memberarea)  
In the menu "Settings" you find "Delete data and account". You can remove your account and the ratings you have created.* Cooperation with Third Parties
The transmission of data to third parties only happens in accordance with the legal requirements. We only pass on data to third parties under permission in accordance with Art. 6 s. 1 a GDPR or on the basis of justified interest according to Art. 6 s. 1 f GDPR in effective and economical operations in our business.  
  
Approval of information processing by third parties is given on the basis of a signed contract DAV/DPA (data processing contract) as per Art. 28 GDPR.* Transmission to Third Countries
The transmission or processing of data to third countries (i.e. outside the EEA (European Economic Area)), with express consent, only occurs if it fulfills a legal obligation or is of justified interest to us. E.g. in using the services of third parties. In this case, the data processing is based on the fact that the EU Commission has determined that a level of data protection similar to that in the EU exists, you have given us your declaration of consent or we have agreed to the standard contractual clauses for the protection of your data with the provider.* Personal Data (Logfiles)
We collect and save information in log files in accordance with Art. [6](https://dejure.org/gesetze/DSGVO/6.html) s. 1 f GDPR (e.g. to resolve cases of misuse or scamming), that your browser automatically transfers to us after requests. The following data is collected:

* Referrer URL (the page from which tellows was accessed)
* Browser type/ -version
* Used operating system
* Web pages viewed during the visit at tellows
* IP address (host name of the accessing computer)
* Date and time of server request
* Transferred data volume
* Requesting provider

All of this data is subject to a special protection in accordance with the regulations under data protection law, which we at tellows and its corresponding applications guarantee through technical and obligatory measures. This data cannot be assigned to any particular person. Merging of this data with other data sources will not be done.  
For security reasons, log file information is stored for a maximum duration of 7 days and then deleted. We reserve the right to store IP addresses for a longer period for law enforcement purposes in the event of a violation of our terms of use.* Use of Cookies

**You can revoke the use of cookies by clicking on the "Cookie setting" link at the bottom of each page on which advertising is loaded.**

We use so-called cookies to allocate your requests from the internet. These small files are automatically stored on your hard drive by your browser for the duration of your stay on our website and are necessary for the accurate use of our website. You can delete the cookies after finishing your stay at our website with certain configurations in your browser. They serve to make our website more user-friendly, effective and secure. For reference for users in California, tellows does not support Do Not Track requests. [You can find further information on the subject of cookies here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/default.aspx)  
  
Our online offerings are also usable under exclusion of cookies. If you do not want cookies to be stored on your computer, you can deactivate the corresponding option in the system settings of your browser. Saved cookies can be deleted in the system settings of the browser. The exclusion of cookies can lead to functional restrictions of this online offer.  
The option to have many online advertising cookies from companies is given via the US website http://www.aboutads.info/choices or the European website [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad- choices/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-%20choices/)  
* Use of Google Analytics
tellows uses Google Analytics, which is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc., (“Google”), 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Web analysis is the collection, storage and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects data including from which website an affected person has come to a website (so-called referrers), which subpages of the website were accessed or how often and for which length of stay a subpage was viewed. A web analysis is mainly used to optimize a website and for the cost-benefit analysis of online advertising. We only use Google Analytics with active IP anonymization. This means that the IP address of the users Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement from the European Economic Area will be shortened. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, which are text files that are stored on your computer and make it possible for us to analyse your use of this website. The information about your use of this website that is generated by means of a cookie is, in most cases, transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymization is activated on this website and you are located in a member state of the European Union or in another contracting state to the Agreement on the European Economic Area, your IP address will first be shortened by Google. Only in exceptional cases will your complete IP address be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website in order to analyze your use of this website, compile reports on website activities, and render further services related to website and internet usage for the operator of this website. In the event that personal data is transferred to the USA, corresponding EU standard contracts (adequate guarantee for data processing in non-European countries) have been concluded with Google LLC. The EU standard contractual clauses used can be accessed via the URL [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32010D0087](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32010D0087). The IP address provided by your browser in the context of Google Analytics will not be merged by Google with other data. You can prevent storage of cookies by means of a setting in your browser software; however, we must advise you that in this case you might not be able to use all the functions of this website to their full extent. Beyond this, you can also prevent collection of the data that is generated by cookies and related to your use of this website (including your IP address) by Google as well as processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the following link. [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). We like to point out, however, that in this case you might not be able to use all the website’s functions to their full extent. By using our website, you agree to the processing of the compiled data by Google in the aforementioned manner and for the aforementioned purpose. For more information about Google's use of data, opt-out and other options, please visit Google's websites:  
* California
_COPPA_  
tellows does not market to children and complies with COPPA as such.  
  
_Do Not Sell My Personal Data_  
tellows does not sell data to third parties. Third party data analytics are, carried out via Google Analytics, as mentioned above using anonymised iP addresses and data encryption.* Advertising Partners
Some of our affiliates may use cookies and web beacons. Our advertising partners include Google Adsense, The Reach Group, Adscale / Ströer, Valuebrand, Snigel Web Services, 1337 UGC GmbH and YieldLove.  
These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology for advertisements and links that appear on tellows and are sent directly to your browser. This automatically gives you your IP address. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) can also be used by third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertising or to personalize the ad content displayed.  
The collection and processing of data is based on the legitimate interest in accordance with Article 6 s. 1 f of the GDPR and by commissioning the processing of data by advertising partners (third parties) with a concluded DAV / DPA ("data processing contract") pursuant to Art. 28 GDPR. tellows has no access or control over these third-party cookies.  
Refer to the Affiliate’s Privacy Policy for details on their practices and how to opt out of specific practices. The tellows privacy policy does not apply to other advertisers or sites, and we cannot control their activities.  
If you want to disable cookies, you can do so through your own browser options. You can find more detailed information about cookie management with certain web browsers on the respective websites of the browsers.* Third Party and Opt-Out Opportunities for YieldLove, Snigeld Web Ltd. and 1337 UGC GmbH
We use SnigelWeb Ltd. as a third-party to provide monetisation technologies for our site. You can review their privacy and cookie policy [here](https://www.snigel.com/privacy-policy/).  
  
A central contradiction possibility for different third-party suppliers in particular US-companies is also attainable under the following link: optout.networkadvertising.org But you can also opt-out separately for each company we work with. Responsible for the data collection and for the delivery of interest based-based online advertising are the following companies on behalf Yieldlove GmbH, Kehrwieder 9, 20457 Hamburg and / or SnigelWeb Ltd., The Black Church, St. Mary’s Place, D07 P4AX and / or 1337 UGC GmbH, Am Sägerhof 3, 90596 Schwanstetten.  
Expand all Partners their opt-outs and privacy policies  

* 4w Marketplace
4w Marketplace (www.4wmarketplace.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of 4w Marketplace is 4w Marketplace srl located in Fisciano (Salerno) – 84084 in Via Giovanni Paolo II n.100. In case you would like to prevent 4w Marketplace from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [http://www.4wmarketplace.com/privacy/](http://www.4wmarketplace.com/privacy/)  
  
Opt-out: [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/it/le-tue-scelte](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/it/le-tue-scelte)  
* Adform
Adform (www.adform.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Adform is Adform located in Wildersgade 10B, 1, 1408 Copenhagen, Denmark. In case you would like to prevent Adform from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/](https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/)  
  
Opt-out: [https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/](https://site.adform.com/privacy-policy-opt-out/)  
* Amazon
Amazon (https://www.aps.amazon.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Amazon publisher services is Amazon publisher services located in Washington – 410 Terry Ave. North, Seattle, WA 98109-5210. In case you would like to prevent Amazon publisher services from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp\_left\_sib?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_left_sib?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496)  
  
Opt-out: [https://www.amazon.com/adprefs/ref=hp\_468496\_advertisingpref2](https://www.amazon.com/adprefs/ref=hp_468496_advertisingpref2)  
* AppNexus
AppNexus (https://www.appnexus.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of AppNexus is AppNexus Group located in in New York – 28 W. 23rd Street, New York, New York, 10010. In case you would like to prevent Appnexus from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/privacy-policy](https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/privacy-policy)  
  
Opt-out: [https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy#choices](https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy#choices)  
* Conversant
Conversant (https://www.conversantmedia.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Conversant is Conversant inc. located in in Chicago (IL) – 101 North Wacker, 23rd Floor Chicago, IL 60606. In case you would like to prevent Conversant from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [http://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy](http://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy)  
  
Opt-out: [http://optout.conversantmedia.com/](http://optout.conversantmedia.com/)  
* Criteo
Criteo (https://www.criteo.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Criteo is Criteo located in Paris – 32 Rue Blanche – 75009 Paris - France. In case you would like to prevent Criteo from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [http://www.criteo.com/privacy/](http://www.criteo.com/privacy/)  
  
Opt-out: [https://www.criteo.com/privacy/](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/)  
* District M
District M (https://districtm.net) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of District M is District M located in Montreal – 5455 Gaspe Ave #730, Montreal, QC H2T 3B3, Canada. In case you would like to prevent District M from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future.  
Privacy policy: [https://districtm.net/en/page/platforms-data-and-privacy-policy/](https://districtm.net/en/page/platforms-data-and-privacy-policy/)  
  
Opt-out: [https://cdn.districtm.ca/optout.html](https://cdn.districtm.ca/optout.html)  
* Doubleclick
Doubleclick (www.doubleclickbygoogle.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Doubleclick is Google located in Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow St Dublin 4 Ireland. In case you would like to prevent Doubleclick from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Opt-out: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en)  
* Facebook
Facebook (www.facebook.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Facebook is Facebook Inc., located in 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. In case you would like to prevent Facebook from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [www.facebook.com/full\_data\_use\_policy](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy)  
Opt-out: [www.facebook.com/ads/preferences](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences)  
* Indexexchange
Indexexchange (www.indexexchange.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Indexexchange is Indexexchange located in New York – 20 W 22nd St. Suite 1101, New York, NY 10010. In case you would like to prevent Indexexchange from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/](http://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/)  
Opt-out: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)  
* Media.net
Media.net (http://www.media.net/privacy-policy) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Media.net is Media.net Advertising Ltd. located in Dubai – 107/108, DIC Building 5, Dubai Internet City, Dubai, 215028, United Arab Emirates. In case you would like to prevent Media.net from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.media.net/privacy-policy](http://www.media.net/privacy-policy)  
Opt-out: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)  
* Oath
Oath (https://www.oath.com/) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Oath is Oath (EMEA) Limited located in Dublin - 5-7 Point Square, North Wall Quay. In case you would like to prevent Oath from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://privacy.aol.com/](http://privacy.aol.com/)  
Opt-out: [https://aim.yahoo.com/aim/ie/en/optout/](https://aim.yahoo.com/aim/ie/en/optout/)  
* OpenX
OpenX (https://www.OpenX.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of OpenX is OpenX located in Pasadena – 888 E Walnut St, 2nd Floor, Pasadena CA, 91101, USA. In case you would like to prevent OpenX from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.openx.com/de\_de/privacy-policy/](https://www.openx.com/de_de/privacy-policy/)  
Opt-out: [https://www.openx.com/legal/interest-based-advertising/](https://www.openx.com/legal/interest-based-advertising/)  
* Pubmatic
Pubmatic (https://www.pubmatic.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Pubmatic is Pubmatic, Inc. located in Redwood City – 305 Main Street, First Floor, Redwood City, California 94063, USA. In case you would like to prevent Pubmatic from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.openx.com/de\_de/privacy-policy/](https://www.openx.com/de_de/privacy-policy/)  
Opt-out: [https://pubmatic.com/legal/opt-out/](https://pubmatic.com/legal/opt-out/)  
* Pulsepoint
Pulsepoint (https://www.pulsepoint.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Pulsepoint is Pulsepoint, Inc. located in New York – 360 Madison Avenue, 14th Floor, New York, NY 10017. In case you would like to prevent Pulsepoint from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy](https://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy)  
Opt-out: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/)  
* Reachnet
Reachnet (https://www.reachnet.de) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Reachnet is Reachnet DE Ltd. located in Hamburg – Grindelallee 41, D-20146 Hamburg. In case you would like to prevent Reachnet from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.reachnet.de/unternehmen/agb.html](http://www.reachnet.de/unternehmen/agb.html)  
Opt-out: [https://adfarm1.adition.com/opt?m=optout&n=73](https://adfarm1.adition.com/opt?m=optout&n=73)  
* Rubicon Project
Rubicon Project (https://www.rubiconproject.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Rubicon Project is Rubicon Project, inc. located in Playa Vista – 12181 Bluff Creek Drive, 4th Floor, Playa Vista, CA 90094, USA. In case you would like to prevent Rubicon Project from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy-policy/](http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy-policy/)  
Opt-out: [https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/](https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/)  
* Primis
Primis (https://www.primis.tech) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Primis is Primis LTD located in 622 Third avenue, McCann New York House 10017 New York City, USA. In case you would like to prevent Primis from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.primis.tech/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/primisPrivacyPolicy2018.pdf](https://www.primis.tech/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/primisPrivacyPolicy2018.pdf)  
Opt-out: https://web.archive.org/web/20180116234711/http:/live.sekindo.com/utils/cookieOptOut.php  
* Smaato
Smaato (https://www.smaato.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Smaato is Smaato Ad Services located in Hamburg – Valentinskamp 70, Emporio, 20355 Hamburg, Germany. In case you would like to prevent Smaato from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.smaato.com/privacy/](https://www.smaato.com/privacy/)  
Opt-out: [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)  
* SmartAdserver
SmartAdserver (https://www.smartadserver.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of SmartAdserver is SmartAdserver located in Paris – 66 Rue de la Chaussée d´Antin, 75009 Paris, France. In case you would like to prevent SmartAdserver from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://smartadserver.com/company/privacy-policy/](http://smartadserver.com/company/privacy-policy/)  
Opt-out: [http://www.smartadserver.com/diffx/optout/IABOptout.aspx](http://www.smartadserver.com/diffx/optout/IABOptout.aspx)  
* Sovrn
Sovrn (https://www.sovrn.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Sovrn is Sovrn Holdings, Inc. located in Boulder – 5541 Central Avenue, Boulder, CO 80301. In case you would like to prevent Sovrn from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy-eu/](https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy-eu/)  
Opt-out: [https://info.evidon.com/pub\_info/15620?v=1&nt=0&nw=false](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/15620?v=1&nt=0&nw=false)  
* Ströer SSP
Ströer SSP (https://www.adscale.de) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Ströer SSP is Ströer media Deutschland GmbH located in Köln – 50999 Köln, Ströer-Allee 1. In case you would like to prevent Adscale from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.adscale.de/datenschutz](http://www.adscale.de/datenschutz)  
Opt-out: [ih.adscale.de/adscale-ih/oo](http://ih.adscale.de/adscale-ih/oo)  
* Twiago
Twiago (https://www.twiago.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Twiago is Twiago located in Köln – Gustav-Heinemann-Ufer 72b, 50968 Köln. In case you would like to prevent Twiago from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://www.twiago.com/datenschutz/](http://www.twiago.com/datenschutz/)  
Opt-out: [http://control.twiago.com/privacy.php?lang=0](http://control.twiago.com/privacy.php?lang=0)  
* Mopub
Mopub (https://www.mopub.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Mopub is Twitter, Inc. located in San Francisco – 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, Ca 94103. In case you would like to prevent Moppub from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.mopub.com/legal/privacy/](https://www.mopub.com/legal/privacy/)  
Opt-out: [https://www.mopub.com/legal/privacy/](https://www.mopub.com/legal/privacy/)  
* Inmobi
Inmobi (https://www.inmobi.com) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Inmobi is Inmobi Pte Ltd located in Bangalore – Embassy Tech Square, Kadubeesanahalli Village Outer Ring Road, Varthur Hobli, Bangalore 560103. In case you would like to prevent Inmobi from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [https://www.inmobi.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.inmobi.com/privacy-policy/)  
Opt-out: [https://www.inmobi.com/page/opt-out/](https://www.inmobi.com/page/opt-out/)  
* Connectad
Connectad (www.connectad.io) uses technologies, to show interest-based advertising to you. Provider of Connectad is Connectad located in Margaretenstrasse 87/11, Vienna, Austria. In case you would like to prevent Connectad from gathering anonymised data you can do so by using the opt-out link below. This Opt-out cookie deletes all gathered information until now and prevents it from collecting any information in the future. Privacy policy: [http://connectadrealtime.com/privacy/](http://connectadrealtime.com/privacy/)  
Opt-out: [http://sync-eu.connectad.io](http://sync-eu.connectad.io/sync/dnt?__hstc=266841809.0a81b953556ce3558cb1f0af90aa4740.1527162622466.1527162622466.1527162622466.1&__hssc=266841809.2.1527162622467&__hsfp=1834479749)  
* OTHER / UNFORESEEN COOKIES
Due to the way in which Internet and websites work, it is possible that we do not always have oversight into the cookies that are placed through our banners by third parties. This is particularly the case when our banners contain embedded elements such as texts, documents, images or film clips that are stored by another party, but that are shown on, in or through our banners. Should you encounter cookies on this website that fall into this category which we have not mentioned above, please let us know or contact the third party directly and ask which cookies they have placed, what the reason for this is, what the lifetime of the cookie is and in what way they have safeguarded your privacy. YOUR RIGHTS WITH REGARDS TO YOUR DATA Yieldlove does not view the banner advertising data it uses as personal data under the applicable law. Likewise, we do not collect or process sensitive personal data such as data on racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, health, or sex life. We also do not knowingly collect data from children under the age of 12.

* Use of Google AdSense / Doubleclick
tellows uses Google Adsense, an advertisement service of Google Inc., Mountain View, USA („Google“). Google Adsense uses „Cookies“ which are stored by your browser (e.g. as small text files) on your computer and which allow an analysis of your usage of this website. Google Adsense also uses so-called „Web Beacons“ (little invisible images) to collect information. By using Web Beacons simple actions like visitor traffic on the website may be recorded and collected. The information about your usage of the website generated by the cookies and/or Web Beacons (including your IP address) will be transmitted to a server of Google in the United States of America and will be stored there. You can prevent the storage of cookies in your browser. In the event that personal data is transferred to the USA, corresponding EU standard contracts (adequate guarantee for data processing in non-European countries) have been concluded with Google LLC. The EU standard contractual clauses used can be accessed via the URL [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32010D0087](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32010D0087). Information collected by Google may be shared with third parties, by contract or by law, by Google. Google will not connect your IP address with other data you have stored. With the corresponding settings on your web browser you can prevent the mentioned cookies from being stored on your PC. However, there is the possibility that the contents of this website can no longer be used to the same extent. By using this site, you consent to the processing of personal data by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. [Further information on the privacy policy of Google AdSense can be found here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
Here, you can disable Googe AdSense Cookies: [https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous)  
and [https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/)  
* Use of the Facebook-Plugin
On these websites, the plugins of the social network facebook.com are utilized, which are run by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA („Facebook“). If you open a website of our web presence with such a plugin, a connection to the Facebook servers is established and the plugin is shown through a message to your browser. Hereby, the Facebook server is signalled about which websites of ours you have visited. If you are logged in as a member of Facebook at that time, Facebook will assign this information to your Facebook user account. By using the plugin functions (e.g. click on the „like“-buttons, writing of comments), this information is also attributed to your Facebook user account, which you can only prevent by logging out before using the plugins. If you are not a member of Facebook, there is still the possibility that Facebook will find out and save your IP address. According to Facebook, only an anonymized IP address is stored. Further information on the gathering and usage of data by Facebook and your respective rights and possibilities to protect your privacy can be found in the [privacy section on Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).* Conversion Tracking Pixel of Facebook and Facebook Custom Audience
With your permission, tellows uses the “conversion tracking pixel” of the Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (Facebook). With this tool we can follow actions of the users after they saw or clicked a Facebook advertisement. Therefore we can record the efficiency of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes. The collected data is anonymous, which means we cannot see the personal data of the user. To our knowledge and your information, Facebook will store and process these data. Facebook is able to connect this data with your Facebook account and use it for its own advertisement purposes according to its own privacy policy you find under [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). You are able to give permission to Facebook and its partners for the use of advertisement in and outside of Facebook. Storing of a cookie on your computer for these purposes is possible. Only users over 13 years of age can declare such permission. If you are younger please ask your legal guardian. Facebook users should note that tellows uses the Website Custom Audience communication tool from Facebook. For this purpose, so-called Facebook pixels are built into our websites. If you are a Facebook user, Facebook is thus able to assign your visit of our website pages to your Facebook user account. Further, Facebook can subsequently find out whether a particular Facebook ad was effective. The Facebook pixel also enables us to distribute ads to defined recipients via Facebook. For this purpose, we exclusively receive statistical data from Facebook that is not related to actual persons. The purpose of this measure is to optimize our website in terms of advertising appeal, market research, and demand-driven design. The pixel-based tracking activities are performed in a way that does not enable us to identify you personally and only marks users as visitors of our website in anonymized form for us. For more information on the purpose and extent of data collection and further processing and use of the data by Facebook as well as the options you have to protect your privacy, please refer to the Facebook data privacy policy that can be found at [https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). Right of revocation: Objections against the use of Facebook Website Custom Audiences can be made at [https://www.facebook.com/ads/website\_custom\_audiences](https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences). For this, you must be logged in to Facebook.* Google Fonts
We are incorporating the fonts ("Google Fonts") provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, to optimize web page loading rates. The integration of these web fonts is done by a server call, usually a Google server in the USA. The websites you have visited will be transferred to the server. Also, the IP address of the browser which has been used by the visitor of this website is stored by Google. The privacy policy can be found at: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and the opt-out at: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated).* Google Library for Ajax and jQuery
We use Ajax and jQuery's JavaScript library to optimize the webpage's loading rate. In this case, program libraries are retrieved from servers of the company Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (Google) specifically the Google CDN. If you have already used jQuery on another page of the Google CDN, your browser will use the cached copy. Otherwise, the required information will be downloaded. In doing so, your visited website will be sent to the Google server. Also, the IP address of your device is stored by Google. For more information, please visit: [https://cloud.google.com/cdn/?hl=en](https://cloud.google.com/cdn/?hl=en) and [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/?hl=en](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/?hl=en). To prevent the execution of JavaScript, you can install a JavaScript Blocker.* Google reCAPTCHA
We use “Google reCAPTCHA” (hereinafter “reCAPTCHA”) on our websites. This service is provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). reCAPTCHA is used to check whether the data entered on our website (such as on a contact form) has been entered by a human or by an automated program. To do this, reCAPTCHA analyzes the behavior of the website visitor based on various characteristics. This analysis starts automatically as soon as the website visitor enters the website. For the analysis, reCAPTCHA evaluates various information (e.g. IP address, how long the visitor has been on the website, or mouse movements made by the user). The data collected during the analysis will be forwarded to Google. The reCAPTCHA analyses take place completely in the background. Website visitors are not advised that such an analysis is taking place. Data processing is based on Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in protecting its site from abusive automated crawling and spam. For more information about Google reCAPTCHA and Google’s privacy policy, please visit: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)  
and [https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/android.html](https://www.google.com/recaptcha/intro/android.html)  
* Google Maps
We use the Google Maps service provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, to illustrate the location of addresses. The privacy policy can be found at: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and the opt-out at: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). Information about your use of our website (such as your IP address) is transferred to Google servers in the USA and stored there when you call up those sub-pages in which the Google Maps map is integrated. This occurs regardless of whether Google provides a user account via which you are logged in or whether no user account exists. If you are logged in to Google, your data will be directly assigned to your account. If you do not want your data to be associated with your Google profile, you must log out of your Google user account. Google stores your data (even for users who are not logged in) as usage profiles and evaluates them. You have the right to object to the creation of these user profiles, and you must contact Google to exercise this right. Google Ireland Limited ensures compliance with the level of data protection applicable in the EU by accepting and agreeing to the so-called EU standard contractual clauses on data protection. If you do not agree to the future transmission of your data to Google in the context of the use of Google Maps, you also have the option of completely deactivating the Google Maps web service by switching off the JavaScript application in your browser. Google Maps and thus also the map display on this website can then not be used. These processing operations are only carried out when explicit consent is given in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR.* OpenStreetMap
This site uses the open source mapping tool "OpenStreetMap" (OSM) via an API. The provider is the OpenStreetMap Foundation. To use the functions of OpenStreetMap, it is necessary to store your IP address. This information is usually transmitted to a server of OpenStreetMap and stored there. The provider of this site has no influence on this data transmission. The use of OpenStreetMap is in the interest of an appealing presentation of our online offers and an easy location of the places indicated by us on the website. This constitutes a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR. By using our website, you consent to the processing of data by OpenStreetMap. The execution of data processing by OpenStreetMap can be prevented by deactivating the Javascript in your browser. However, this will prevent the OpenStreetMap map view from being displayed. More information on the handling of user data can be found on the [privacy page](https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Legal_FAQ) of OpenStreetMap and here [http://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Legal\_FAQ](https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Legal_FAQ).* ShareThis Social Media Buttons on the tellows Blog
On our blog we use the service of ShareThis to provide social media sharing tools. ShareThis collects information via technical cookies placed on your browser, pixel tags, HTTP headers (or other communication protocols), and browser identifiers. No flash cookies or other locally stored objects (LSO) are used to circumvent user opt-out choices. ShareThis collects registration information and Usage Data. Usage Data collects and uses technical data relating to some of your browsing to display personalized advertisements, provide analytics, and data modeling based on social sharing. ShareThis does not at any point collect contact information such as your name, address, phone number, address, credit card information, or anything else that can allow us or our clients to contact you directly. ShareThis shares Usage Data, including audience segments, with advertisers, Publishers, and other data partners (all, “Our Customers”) for interest-based advertising, analytics and data modeling. The cookies used in connection with ShareThis have a storage period of up to 9 months. For more information on the handling of user data, please refer to the ShareThis privacy policy at [HTTPS://SHARETHIS.COM/PRIVACY/](https://sharethis.com/PRIVACY/).* SSL Encryption
tellows uses SSL encryption for security and to protect the transmission of sensitive content, such as the requests you send to the site operator. You can recognize an encrypted connection by changing the address line of the browser from "http://" to "https://" and the lock symbol in your browser bar. If SSL encryption is enabled, the data you submit to us cannot be read by third parties.* OpenID Login
No registration is required to participate in the tellows forum. Comments can be submitted as a registered or unregistered user. An OpenID service can be used to register. Thereby, an existing account of another service (e.g. Google) is linked to the tellows website through an authentication system. No separate account is created on the tellows website. Linking an account through OpenID enables additional options for comments and account settings on tellows. OpenID users are registered with the e-mail address of the linked account. The e-mail address must always be accessible to the user in order to be contacted for possible queries on the part of tellows. The use of an invalid e-mail address is not permitted. The data entered during registration will be used for the purpose of using the website. Users may be informed by email about website- or registration-related information, such as changes in the scope of the offer or technical circumstances. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the user's protection against misuse and other unauthorized use.* tellows in Social Networks
To also communicate with you on social networks and inform you about our services, we are represented there with our own pages. If you visit one of our social media pages, we are jointly responsible with the provider of the respective social media platform within the meaning of Art. 26 GDPR with regard to the processing operations triggered thereby which concern personal data. We are not the original provider of these pages, but merely use them within the scope of the possibilities offered to us by the respective providers. As a precaution, we therefore point out that your data may also be processed outside the European Union or the European Economic Area. Use may therefore entail data protection risks for you, as it may be more difficult to protect your rights, e.g. to information, deletion, objection, etc., and the processing in the social networks often takes place directly for advertising purposes or for the analysis of user behaviour by the providers, without this being able to be influenced by us. If usage profiles are created by the provider, cookies are often used or the usage behaviour is directly assigned to your own member profile of the social networks (if you are logged in here). The described processing of personal data is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR on the basis of our legitimate interest and the legitimate interest of the respective provider in order to be able to communicate with you in a timely manner or to inform you about our services. If you have to give your consent to data processing as a user with the respective providers, the legal basis refers to Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR in conjunction with Art. 7 GDPR. As we do not have access to the providers' databases, we would like to point out that it is best to exercise your rights (e.g. to information, correction, deletion, etc.) directly with the respective provider. Further information on the processing of your data in the social networks and the possibility to make use of your right of objection or revocation (so-called opt-out) is listed below at the respective provider of social networks used by us:

* Facebook
(Co-) controller for data processing in Europe: Facebook Ireland Ltd, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. Privacy Policy (Data Policy): [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy)  
Opt-out and advertising preferences: [https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry\_product=ad\_settings\_screen](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen)  
Facebook ensures compliance with the level of data protection applicable in the EU by accepting and agreeing to the so-called EU standard contractual clauses on data protection. [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)  
* Instagram
(Co-)responsible for data processing in Europe: Facebook Ireland Ltd, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. Privacy Policy (Data Policy): [http://instagram.com/legal/privacy/](https://instagram.com/legal/privacy/)  
Opt-out and advertising preferences: [https://www.instagram.com/accounts/privacy\_and\_security/](https://www.instagram.com/accounts/privacy_and_security/)  
Instagram ensures compliance with the level of data protection applicable in the EU by accepting and agreeing to the so-called EU standard contractual clauses on data protection.* LinkedIn
(Co-) controller for data processing in Europe: LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland. Privacy Policy: [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)  
Opt-out and advertising preferences: [https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out)  
* X (Twitter)
Data controller in Europe: Twitter International Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, D02 AX07, Ireland. Privacy Policy: [https://twitter.com/en/privacy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy)  
Information about your data: [https://twitter.com/settings/your\_twitter\_data](https://twitter.com/settings/your_twitter_data)  
Opt-out and advertising preferences: [https://twitter.com/personalization](https://twitter.com/personalization)  

* Comments in the Forum
When you post or rate a comment in the forum, your IP address will be stored. This is a security measure, in case someone publishes illegal content (insults, prohibited political propaganda, etc.). In this case, tellows could be prosecuted for the content. Therefore, we are interested in the identity of the comment author. It is possible to subscribe to the number pages. To do so, you must enter your e-mail address. You will receive a confirmation email to verify that you are the owner of the entered email address. You can unsubscribe from the notifications at any time. The confirmation email contains instructions.* Right of removal of comments on a telephone number
On tellows, every user can leave comments regarding any telephone number. These comments represent the opinion of the comment’s author and **not the opinion of tellows on that phone number**. Which is why we created an option to delete comments. Under every comment, there is a button called „Report the comment as spam“. With a simple click on this button, comments are directly deleted. Comments from registered users who have a tellows account cannot be removed by other users. In this case it is necessary to inform us by email to kontaktATtellows.de about the removal request. Registered tellows users have the opportunity to comment on the deletion request within 48 hours. If no credible statement is made, the comment will be removed. More information about comment removals for registered users can be found [here](https://tellows.de/c/about-tellows-uk/terms-of-use/#termsofuseforum).* Right of Information
You have the right to obtain the information about your person any time. If you have further questions regarding the privacy policy or need more information on a certain point, you can contact our data protection officer at datenschutzATtellows.de (replace AT with a @).* Right to Erasure
The data subject shall have the right to obtain from the controller the erasure of personal data concerning him or her without undue delay and the controller shall have the obligation to erase personal data without undue delay where one of the following grounds applies:

* the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed;
* the data subject withdraws consent on which the processing is based according to point a of Art. 6 s. 1, or point a of Art. 9 s. 2, and where there is no other legal ground for the processing;
* the data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Art. 21 s. 1 and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing, or the data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Art. 21 s. 2;
* the personal data has been unlawfully processed;
* the personal data has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation in Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject;
* the personal data has been collected in relation to the offer of information services referred to in Art. 8 s. 1.

Where the controller has made the personal data public and is obliged to erase the personal data, the controller, taking account of available technology and the cost of implementation, shall take reasonable steps, including technical measures, to inform controllers which are processing the personal data that the data subject has requested the erasure by such controllers of any links to, or copy, or replication of, those personal data. This right shall not apply to the extent that processing is necessary for erasure (“right to be forgotten”). This includes the following requirements:

* exercising the right of freedom of expression and information;
* compliance with a legal obligation which requires processing by Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller;
* the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

* Right to Restriction of Processing
The data subject shall have the right to obtain from the controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies:

* the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject, for a period enabling the controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data;
* the processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests the restriction of their use instead;
* the controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but they are required by the data subject for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims;
* the data subject has objected to processing pursuant to Art. 21 s. 1 pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of the controller override those of the data subject.

Where processing has been restricted under s. 1, such personal data shall, with the exception of storage, only be processed with the data subject’s consent or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims or for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest of the Union or of a Member State. In order to allege the right to restriction of processing, the data subject can contact us at any time under datenschutzATtellows.de (replace AT with @).* Right to Data Portability
The data subject shall have the right to receive the personal data concerning him or her, which he or she has provided to a controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and has the right to transmit this data to another controller without hindrance from the controller to which the personal data has been provided, where:

* the processing is based on consent pursuant to point a of Art. 6 s. 1 or point a of Art. 9 s. 2 or on a contract pursuant to point b of Article 6 s.1 GDPR; and
* the processing is carried out by automated means.

In exercising his or her right to data portability pursuant to s. 1, the data subject shall have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible. The exercise of the right of removal shall be unaffected. That right shall not apply to processing necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller.* Right to Object
The data subject shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her which is based on point e or f of Art. 6 s. 1, including profiling based on those provisions. The controller shall no longer process the personal data unless the controller demonstrates compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. Where personal data are processed for direct marketing purposes, the data subject shall have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. In the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, the data subject may exercise his or her right to object by automated means using technical specifications. Please contact datenschutzATtellows.de for an objection (replace AT with @).* Automated Individual Decision-Making, Including Profiling
The data subject shall have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her. This shall not apply if the decision:

* is necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between the data subject and a data controller;
* is authorised by Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject and which also lays down suitable measures to safeguard the data subject’s rights and freedoms and legitimate interests; or
* is based on the data subject’s explicit consent.

In these cases, the data controller shall implement suitable measures to safeguard the data subject’s rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, at least the right to obtain human intervention on the part of the controller, to express his or her point of view and to contest the decision. This right can be exercised by the affected person at any time by addressing himself to the responsible person.* Right to Complain to a Regulating Authority
Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you have the right to complain to a regulating authority, in particular in the Member State of your residence, place of work or place of alleged infringement, if the person in subject considers that the processing of the personal data infringes this Regulation.* Right to Effective Legal Remedy
Without prejudice to any available administrative or non-legal remedy, including the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority pursuant to Art. 77, each data subject shall have the right to an effective legal remedy where he or she considers that his or her rights under this Regulation have been infringed as a result of the processing of his or her personal data in non-compliance with this Regulation.* Questions about Privacy
If further questions or suggestions regarding the subject of privacy might arise, please contact our data privacy officer Christian Anton at datenschutzATtellows.de (replace the AT with @).

**Use of Data in the tellows Applications**

-----------------------------------------------

At tellows, we are keenly aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to protect your privacy. We comply with the data protection regulations of the European Union regarding your personal data. This disclaimer refers only to our tellows applications. Third parties might offer hyperlinks to other websites which may have information policies and practices different from ours. We do not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies, practices, or the content of any third party Web sites. Once you've left our websites via such a link or by clicking on an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party or advertiser site to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you. tellows uses the submitted comments and ratings from the tellows website and applications to evaluate telephone numbers in applications. No personal data of the comment’s author is used or stored in this process. Only the submitted comments and the resulting ratings are used to categorize the telephone numbers. Applications, based on this information are run by tellows and by third parties working in a contractual relationship.* tellows iOS Applications
To ensure the full extent of the premium iOS-applications “tellows pro Caller ID” and “tellows - Reverse Search” features, during installation, the creation of three new contacts in your smartphone is necessary. In these contacts, the score lists are saved, giving its user information about the type and rating of an undesired caller. During installation, the approval to access the smartphone’s contacts is a requirement. Personal contacts and data is not accessed. The iPhone app "tellows Caller ID & Block" imports the score lists into the internal storage of the iPhone. The detailed terms of use for the iPhone apps can be found here: [https://www.tellows.co.uk/c/about-tellows-uk/terms-of-use/#termsofuseapp](https://www.tellows.co.uk/c/about-tellows-uk/terms-of-use/#termsofuseapp)  
* Push notification
In order to ensure the latest status of the score list, the sending of push notifications is essential. The basis for data processing in connection with the sending of push notifications is your consent. You can revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. To do so, it is best to simply deactivate push notifications on your end device. You can deactivate the push notifications on your mobile device at any time under "Messages" in the "tellows Caller ID & Blocker" tab.* tellows Android app
At tellows, we are keenly aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to protect your privacy. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining of our online information practices, including how we collect and use the information you may provide to us on the website, and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. We comply with the data protection regulations of the European Union regarding your personal data. This disclaimer refers only to our sites and app "tellows - Caller ID & Block". Third parties might offer hyperlinks to other websites which may have information policies and practices different from ours. We do not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies, practices, or the content of any third party Web sites. Once you\\'ve left our websites via such a link or by clicking on an advertisement, you should check the applicable privacy policy of the third party or advertiser site to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you.* Use of data in the tellows Application
The tellows Android app registers incoming calls and sends the phone number to tellows to compare it with the blacklist and block it if necessary. With the submission of comments and the resulting ratings, phone numbers are classified. When a rating is submitted, the rated telephone number and the associated data such as comment and user name are sent to tellows. When a rating is submitted, the IP address is also transmitted to tellows. The removal of content can be done with the help of a spam button. Telephone numbers of incoming calls are sent to our server to provide anonymised caller statistics and activities on spam telephone numbers. Numbers from your own contacts are not transferred to tellows if contact sharing permission has been granted. When using the premium version, a personal block list is imported into the phone, which is used to identify and block the numbers on the block list. The phone number is added by the application. Personal contacts and data remain unaffected.* Permissions of the tellows Android app
To ensure the full functionality of the tellows app, the following permissions must be granted prior to use:

* **Call logs**  
    Comparison of telephone numbers with the tellows database and assignment of a scoring, if the telephone number of the incoming call does not exist in your existing contacts.
* **Make and manage phone calls**  
    View caller information or block the phone number during an incoming call. Therefore unknown phone numbers from incoming calls are sent to our servers.
* **Contacts**  
    Granting the permission to share contacts ensures that only unknown phone numbers are checked by tellows and no contacts that you already know. With the permission contacts are excluded from identification and do not receive a tellows scoring. Personal contacts will not be sent to tellows.
* **Receive SMS (optional)**  
    View information about unknown phone number after receiving SMS. If enabled unknown phone numbers from the SMS Log are send to the tellows server for identification.

* Personal data
Personal data is individual information about personal and factual circumstances of an identified or identifiable natural person. In other words, information that identifies a person or at least makes him or her identifiable. All this data is subject to special protection in accordance with data protection regulations, which we ensure on tellows and the associated applications through technical and organisational measures. This data is only used for the purpose of statistical evaluations and to optimise the website, as well as to prevent misuse. The following data is collected when you use the tellows app or mobile website:

* Referrer URL (entry page reached via tellows)
* Browser type/version
* Operating system used
* Internet pages viewed during the visit to tellows
* IP address (host name of the accessing computer)
* The date and time of the server request

The detailed terms of use for the Android App can be found here: [https://www.tellows.co.uk/c/about-tellows-uk/terms-of-use/#termsofuseappandroid](https://www.tellows.co.uk/c/about-tellows-uk/terms-of-use/#termsofuseappandroid)  
* Use of Google Admob in the Android Application
For advertising, we use the advertising partner AdMob Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). Admob stores user data in order to display ads that are relevant to you. These ads appear only in the free app version. Google Admob uses cookies that are stored on your computer and that allow you to analyze the use of the app by you. In addition, Google Admob also uses so-called "web beacons" (small invisible graphics) to collect and evaluate simple actions such as visitor traffic on the website. The information about the usage of this app generated by the cookie and / or web beacon (including your IP address) is usually transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google uses the obtained information to evaluate your usage behavior with respect to the Google Admob ads. The IP address submitted by your browser will not be merged with other Google data. The information collected by Google may be transferred to third parties, if required by law and / or as far as third parties process this data on behalf of Google. You may permanently opt-out of setting a cookie by changing the settings on your browser software or by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: [http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin?hl=en](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin?hl=en)  
Please note that certain features of this app may not be used or may be of limited use if you have objected to the use of cookies.  
  
The data generated in this context can be transmitted by Google to a server in the USA for evaluation and stored there. In the event that personal data is transferred to the USA, corresponding EU standard contracts (appropriate guarantee for data processing in non-European countries) have been concluded with Google LLC. You can find the EU standard contractual clauses used via the URL [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN).* Use of Google Firebase in the Android and iOS Applications
Our app uses Google Firebase technology (Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, "Google"). Firebase is part of the Google Cloud Platform and offers many services to developers. Some Firebase services process personal information. In most cases, the personal data is limited to so-called "instance IDs" that are time-stamped. Firebase\\'s Instance IDs are unique, allowing you to link different events or processes. These data are neither personally identifiable information nor do we make efforts to personalize it afterwards. We process this summarized data for the analysis and optimization of the usage behavior, as for example by the evaluation of crash reports. We do not use Firebase services that use personally identifiable information, such as IP addresses, e-mail addresses, telephone numbers or passwords. The data generated in this context can be transmitted by Google to a server in the USA for evaluation and stored there. In the event that personal data is transferred to the USA, corresponding EU standard contracts (appropriate guarantee for data processing in non-European countries) have been concluded with Google LLC. You can find the EU standard contractual clauses used via the URL [https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087&from=EN). More information on Google Firebase and privacy can be found at [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
as well as [https://firebase.google.com/](https://firebase.google.com/).* Use of Crashlytics in the Android and iOS Applications
Our app uses the analytical tools from Crashlytics, 1 Kendall Square, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA. It uses information about the device, the version of the app you have installed, and other information that can help troubleshoot errors. These relate primarily to the software and hardware of the user. No personal data will be transmitted. Only real-time crash reports will be sent, with details of codes and device information designed to simplify maintenance and improve the resulting stability of the app. This tool uses anonymized IP addresses for analysis purposes. Therefore, it cannot be determined who is the user of the IP address concerned.* Use of Facebook SDK in the Android and iOS Applications
Furthermore, the app uses the so-called Facebook Software Development Kit (SDK). The Facebook SDK is published and administered by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook") (legal basis is Art. 6 (1) lit. GDPR) The use of the Facebook SDK enables us to optimize the advertising success on Facebook via the app by, for example, not displaying ads on those devices on which the app is already installed. For this purpose, the app transmits the following pseudonymized data to Facebook: The App ID (identical on all devices), the information that the app has been started and provided by the operating system of the device Advertising Identifier (IDFA). Further data will not be transmitted to Facebook. We also do not receive any data back from Facebook that could allow us to identify users. By using the app, the user declares their consent to the integration of the Facebook SDK and the associated collection, storage, transfer and processing of user data to the extent described. The information collected in this way is not linked to personal information from tellows users in the analysis software. In this context, user data can also be transmitted to servers in the USA.* Right of Information
You have the right to obtain the information about your person any time. If you have further questions regarding the privacy policy or need more information on a certain point, you can contact our data protection officer at [\[email protected\]](https://www.tellows.co.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).* Right of removal of comments on a telephone number
On tellows, every user can leave comments regarding any telephone number. These comments represent the opinion of the comment's author and not the opinion of tellows on that phone number. Which is why we created an option to delete comments. Under every comment in the mobile version of the website (not in the app), there is a button called "Report the comment as spam". With a simple click on this button, comments are directly deleted.* Questions about Privacy
If further questions or suggestions regarding the subject of privacy might arise, please contact our data privacy officer Christian Anton at [\[email protected\]](https://www.tellows.co.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

* * *

**Your phone is ringing and you don't know who is calling?**

tellows provides information to identify trustworthy or potential risk calls - thanks to our worldwide community.

Cookie Settings

###### Products

###### About tellows

###### News & Media

© 2010-2024 **tellows**
